<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cayco Gajic Lab</title>
    <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cayco Gajic Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Cayco Gajic Lab, 2026 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://caycogajiclab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning in the overparametrized brain</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/overparam-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/overparam-jc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curl Descent : Non-Gradient Learning Dynamics with Sign-Diverse Plasticity</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/curl-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/curl-descent/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of gap junctions and clustered connectivity in emergent synchronization patterns of inhibitory neuronal networks</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/gap-junctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/gap-junctions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed learning across fast and slow neural systems supports efficient motor adaptation</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/cerebellocortical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/cerebellocortical/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality reduction beyond neural subspaces with slice tensor component analysis</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/slicetca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/slicetca/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of gap junctions and clustered connectivity in emergent synchronisation patterns of inhibitory neuronal networks</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/mli-neural-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/mli-neural-mass/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signatures of task learning in neural representations</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/signaturesoflearningreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/signaturesoflearningreview/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar interneuron activity is triggered by reach endpoint during learning of a complex locomotor task</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/loco-reach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/loco-reach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low tensor rank learning of neural dynamics</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/ltr-rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/ltr-rnn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does the neocortex need the cerebellum for working memory?</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/journal-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/journal-club/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar granule cell axons support high-dimensional representations</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/granule-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/granule-cells/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-evaluating circuit mechanisms underlying pattern separation</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/pattern-separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/pattern-separation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparse synaptic connectivity is required for decorrelation and pattern separation in feedforward networks</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/sparse-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/sparse-connectivity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Cayco Gajic</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/alex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/alex/</guid>
      <description>I am a Professor in the Departement D’Etudes Cognitives at ENS with affiliations in the ENS-PSL Quantitative Biology Center (Qbio) and the Paris AI Research Institute (PRAIRIE). My research interests lie at the intersection of neuroscience, machine learning, and mathematical modeling. I am mathematically omnivorous, and my work draws on a variety of tools spanning dynamical systems, matrix and tensor analysis, differential geometry, probabilistic modeling, and high-dimensional statistics. In 2024 I was awarded and ERC Consolidator grant to investigate how latent dynamics in neural populations evolve during learning, with a focus on motor learning in complex tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liana Akobian</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/liana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/liana/</guid>
      <description>I am a Research Assistant at the Group for Neural Theory at Ecole Normale Supérieure in Paris.
Before, I worked at the Zimmer Lab, where I studied the neural dynamics of C. elegans as part of my thesis. My research focused on developing data-driven computational models to disambiguate intrinsic (autonomous) dynamics and actuated (non-autonomous or control) dynamics.
I am currently using Schur Decomposition methods to identify interpretable representations of RNN weights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mattia Della Vecchia</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/mattia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/mattia/</guid>
      <description>Since 2022, I have been a QLife PhD student in the Cayco-Gajic lab, where I investigate how the brain learns through interactions with its environment. My research combines deep reinforcement learning with experimental neural data to uncover the mechanisms underlying motor learning, adaptation, and error-driven control.
During my undergraduate studies in electrical engineering and theoretical physics, I developed a strong interest in artificial intelligence and neuroscience, and in how the two fields can mutually inform one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/alumni/heike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/alumni/heike/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/alumni/helen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/alumni/helen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</guid>
      <description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.
Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arno Granier</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/arno/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/arno/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher at Ecole Normale Supérieure within the group of N Alex Cayco-Gajic. I studied computational neuroscience at University of Bern (with Walter Senn) and the Institute of Neuroinformatics Zürich (with Matthew Cook). My interests span continual learning in recurrent networks, compressed generative encoding of neural connectivity, and computaitonal implication of cell-type-specific connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Ninou</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. in the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris under the joint supervision of Alex Cayco Gajic and Jonathan Kadmon.
My work focuses on the dynamics of learning in biologically plausible neural networks. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in the Hebbian dynamics of learning, its involvement in representational drift and potential applications to AI systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian Brandon</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/julian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/julian/</guid>
      <description>I am a research assistant at the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris. My interests are in learning dynamics, dynamical systems, and geometry-based methods for computational neuroscience and machine learning.
My masters thesis focused on applying a Riemannian geometric framework to understand neural representations across learning regimes in neural networks, under the supervision of Angus Chadwick and Arthur Pellegrino.
I am currently researching mode collapse in generative flow models, with a view of linking this to low-rank biases across training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Agueci</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/leo/</guid>
      <description>My current research focuses on understanding the role of cerebellum during learning. I did my Ph.D. with Alex, probing the cerebello-cortical loop during motor learning and behavior using recurrent neural networks.Previously, I was a research assistant in the group of Andrea Calimera, EDA, Politecnico di Torino, working in machine learning techniques application on predictive maintenance in the MADEin4 and R3-PowerUP european projects, and on development of neural network properties verification algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luis Riquelme</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/luis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/luis/</guid>
      <description>Before my postdoc with Alex Cayco-Gajic, I was a postdoc with Gilles Laurent at the Max Planck Institute for Brain Research in Frankfurt. I did my Ph.D. with Julijana Gjorgjieva at the Technical University of Munich. My BSc and MSc were in computer science and I have experience as a professional software engineer.
During my PhD and first postdoc, I studied reptile brains, from cortical dynamics in turtles to multi-area coordination during lizard sleep, to extract general principles of brain function from an evolutionary perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/overview/</guid>
      <description>Research Overview Our lab studies how learning unfolds in both neural populations and in artificial networks, with an overall aim to link the rules governing weight updates with representational changes and network-level computations.
A central focus of our research is how learning shapes population dynamics to produce new computations. We build mathematical models using both theoretical and data-driven approaches. First, we study the dynamics of gradient flow and biologically-inspired alternatives to understand how the structure of learning rules influences representational geometry and overall model behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>