<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cayco Gajic Lab</title>
    <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cayco Gajic Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Cayco Gajic Lab, 2022 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caycogajiclab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The role of gap junctions and clustered connectivity in emergent synchronisation patterns of inhibitory neuronal networks</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/mli-neural-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/mli-neural-mass/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signatures of task learning in neural representations</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/signaturesoflearningreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/signaturesoflearningreview/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar interneuron activity is triggered by reach endpoint during learning of a complex locomotor task</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/loco-reach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/loco-reach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low tensor rank learning of neural dynamics</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/ltr-rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/ltr-rnn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling mixed classes of covariability in large-scale neural data</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/slicetca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/slicetca/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does the neocortex need the cerebellum for working memory?</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/journal-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/journal-club/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar granule cell axons support high-dimensional representations</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/granule-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/granule-cells/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-evaluating circuit mechanisms underlying pattern separation</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/pattern-separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/pattern-separation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparse synaptic connectivity is required for decorrelation and pattern separation in feedforward networks</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/sparse-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/publication/sparse-connectivity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Cayco Gajic</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/alex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/alex/</guid>
      <description>I am a Junior Professor in the Departement D’Etudes Cognitives at ENS. My formal training lies squarely in applied mathematics, and I completed my PhD under the supervision of Eric Shea Brown at the University of Washington. Throughout my PhD I became increasingly interested in neuroscience, and wanted to learn more about the kinds of questions that were important to experimental neuroscientists. For my postdoc, I decided to join Angus Silver’s Angus Silver&amp;rsquo;s lab at UCL, where I began to focus on the cerebellar circuit while working closely with the experimentalists in his team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heike Stein</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/heike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/heike/</guid>
      <description>Since 2020, I am a postdoc with Alex Cayco Gajic at the Group for Neural Theory. Before that, I obtained my PhD from the Universitat de Barcelona, Spain, where I worked with Albert Compte to understand how NMDA receptor dysfunction affects working memory by altering prefrontal attractor dynamics.
In my postdoc, I am diving into the fields of motor learning and naturalistic behavior, the cerebellum, and how the cerebellum interacts with the neocortex to guide behavior and learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helen Todd</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/helen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/helen/</guid>
      <description>I am currently doing a PhD under the co-supervision of Boris Gutkin and Alex Cayco-Gajic at ENS Paris. My thesis focuses on modelling rapid synchronisation of interneurons in the cerebellum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mattia Della Vecchia</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/mattia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/mattia/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student at the Group for Neural Theory at Ecole Normale Supérieure in Paris . I have interests at the interface of Computational Neuroscience and Artificial Intelligence.
I performed my bachelor internship in the laboratory of Luca Berdondini at Italian Institute of Technology on large-scale neural recordings, spike sorting, and clustering. My master thesis focused on stochastic gradient descent methods for training recurrent neural networks inspired by biological findings under the supervision of Vincent Hakim at LPENS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</guid>
      <description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.
Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Ninou</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. in the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris under the joint supervision of Alex Cayco Gajic and Jonathan Kadmon.
My work focuses on the dynamics of learning in biologically plausible neural networks. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in the Hebbian dynamics of learning, its involvement in representational drift and potential applications to AI systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Agueci</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/leo/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. in the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris. I am currently working on probing the cerebello-cortical loop during motor learning and behavior through mMachine learning and mathematical techniques.Previously, I was a research assistant in the group of Andrea Calimera, EDA, Politecnico di Torino, working in machine learning techniques application on predictive maintenance in the MADEin4 and R3-PowerUP european projects, and on development of neural network properties verification algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mission of the group</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/overview/</guid>
      <description>Research Overview The central aim of our research is to understand the cerebellum’s role in behaviour.
The cerebellum is a unique region because of its evolutionarily-conserved, structured architecture and key role in motor learning. Inspired by its so-called ‘crystalline’ circuitry, classic theories have argued that the cerebellum performs sensorimotor prediction in order to coordinate, adapt, and fine-tune movements during learning.
However, over the past several years, accumulating evidence in humans and mice has hinted that the cerebellum plays a subtle, yet important, role in cognitive processing as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
