<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on Cayco Gajic Lab</title>
    <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on Cayco Gajic Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Cayco Gajic Lab, 2026 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Cayco Gajic</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/alex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/alex/</guid>
      <description>I am a Professor in the Departement D’Etudes Cognitives at ENS with affiliations in the ENS-PSL Quantitative Biology Center (Qbio) and the Paris AI Research Institute (PRAIRIE). My research interests lie at the intersection of neuroscience, machine learning, and mathematical modeling. I am mathematically omnivorous, and my work draws on a variety of tools spanning dynamical systems, matrix and tensor analysis, differential geometry, probabilistic modeling, and high-dimensional statistics. In 2024 I was awarded and ERC Consolidator grant to investigate how latent dynamics in neural populations evolve during learning, with a focus on motor learning in complex tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liana Akobian</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/liana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/liana/</guid>
      <description>I am a Research Assistant at the Group for Neural Theory at Ecole Normale Supérieure in Paris.
Before, I worked at the Zimmer Lab, where I studied the neural dynamics of C. elegans as part of my thesis. My research focused on developing data-driven computational models to disambiguate intrinsic (autonomous) dynamics and actuated (non-autonomous or control) dynamics.
I am currently using Schur Decomposition methods to identify interpretable representations of RNN weights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mattia Della Vecchia</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/mattia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/mattia/</guid>
      <description>Since 2022, I have been a QLife PhD student in the Cayco-Gajic lab, where I investigate how the brain learns through interactions with its environment. My research combines deep reinforcement learning with experimental neural data to uncover the mechanisms underlying motor learning, adaptation, and error-driven control.
During my undergraduate studies in electrical engineering and theoretical physics, I developed a strong interest in artificial intelligence and neuroscience, and in how the two fields can mutually inform one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arno Granier</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/arno/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/arno/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher at Ecole Normale Supérieure within the group of N Alex Cayco-Gajic. I studied computational neuroscience at University of Bern (with Walter Senn) and the Institute of Neuroinformatics Zürich (with Matthew Cook). My interests span continual learning in recurrent networks, compressed generative encoding of neural connectivity, and computaitonal implication of cell-type-specific connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Ninou</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. in the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris under the joint supervision of Alex Cayco Gajic and Jonathan Kadmon.
My work focuses on the dynamics of learning in biologically plausible neural networks. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in the Hebbian dynamics of learning, its involvement in representational drift and potential applications to AI systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian Brandon</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/julian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/julian/</guid>
      <description>I am a research assistant at the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris. My interests are in learning dynamics, dynamical systems, and geometry-based methods for computational neuroscience and machine learning.
My masters thesis focused on applying a Riemannian geometric framework to understand neural representations across learning regimes in neural networks, under the supervision of Angus Chadwick and Arthur Pellegrino.
I am currently researching mode collapse in generative flow models, with a view of linking this to low-rank biases across training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Agueci</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/leo/</guid>
      <description>My current research focuses on understanding the role of cerebellum during learning. I did my Ph.D. with Alex, probing the cerebello-cortical loop during motor learning and behavior using recurrent neural networks.Previously, I was a research assistant in the group of Andrea Calimera, EDA, Politecnico di Torino, working in machine learning techniques application on predictive maintenance in the MADEin4 and R3-PowerUP european projects, and on development of neural network properties verification algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luis Riquelme</title>
      <link>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/luis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caycogajiclab.github.io/member/luis/</guid>
      <description>Before my postdoc with Alex Cayco-Gajic, I was a postdoc with Gilles Laurent at the Max Planck Institute for Brain Research in Frankfurt. I did my Ph.D. with Julijana Gjorgjieva at the Technical University of Munich. My BSc and MSc were in computer science and I have experience as a professional software engineer.
During my PhD and first postdoc, I studied reptile brains, from cortical dynamics in turtles to multi-area coordination during lizard sleep, to extract general principles of brain function from an evolutionary perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>